<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://melb.enix.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://melb.enix.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-09T14:53:57+01:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MelBlog</title><subtitle>Eclipse, modeling and other things</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Meet Sirius in the browser</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/09/siriusweb/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Sirius in the browser" /><published>2022-02-09T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-09T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/09/siriusweb</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/09/siriusweb/">&lt;p&gt;TLDR; This post is for you if you want to build web-based graphical modeling tools.
Eclipse Sirius is an open source project to create domain-specific modeling workbenches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, if you are not aware of “modeling and domain specific blablabla”, you might wonder &lt;em&gt;“What does she mean and why should I care about this?”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give semantics to your drawing…&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is simple, you have &lt;strong&gt;data&lt;/strong&gt; (and I am pretty sure you have some, everyone has data nowadays :)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/data_pipeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;Data Pipeline&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you want to &lt;strong&gt;represent&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;edit&lt;/strong&gt; them in a visual way: diagram, table, forms, dashboard… You have so many ideas! You can visualize it already in your head! But you also want to &lt;strong&gt;exploit&lt;/strong&gt; the information stored in your dataset…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First option, you can use sheets, databases, low code platforms to represent and store your data and you can map your data to charts, forms… This is what you do with tools like Excel, Google Sheets, Airtable, and many low code tools… but but there is no way to represent them on a diagram ;(&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Second option, you can represent your data graphically… thanks to tools like Miro or draw.io… but but then you are stuck! It is just a drawing, you cannot exploit the semantics of your data ;(&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Holy crap… what could I do ?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come here… I have a secret to share with you: you should use Sirius!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirius allows you to &lt;strong&gt;represent your data&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;map them to graphical representations&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;take advantage of your data’s semantic&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Sirius Web? And OCP?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirius has two flavors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sirius Desktop: to create modeling workbenches based on the Eclipse platform,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sirius Web: to create cloud-ready modeling workbenches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriusweb/architecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, as we are very greedy, we provide the Obeo Cloud Platform (OCP) as Sirius Web topping. OCP is a set of Cloud-based products for easily building and deploying modeling studios to the web for enterprise use cases. We offer the Obeo Studio to create graphical modeling solutions that can be used collaboratively from a web browser.
It is built as an open-core product relying on Sirius Web. It is a Sirius Web build extended with Enterprise features, to deploy on public, private clouds or on premise and including support and upgrade guarantees.
One more option for you is to use the components from Sirius Web and OCP to integrate in your own application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you are asking yourself &lt;em&gt;“Ok, I got it but what can I do concretely?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Define your domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing to do is to describe your data. You can use Sirius Web to define your concepts and how they are related to each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I need a tool to represent all the things I have to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I create a new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Domain&lt;/code&gt; with the following concepts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TodoList&lt;/code&gt;: contains all I want to get out of my head :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/code&gt;: my end goal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;KeyResult&lt;/code&gt;: how I know that my goal is achieved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriusweb/domain.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An objective is associated with one or more key results. They are all describes thanks to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Map to visual representation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step is to decide how you want to represent your data, for that you have to create a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;View&lt;/code&gt;. For my to-do list tooling, I decide to represent it with a &lt;strong&gt;diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a graphical &lt;em&gt;node&lt;/em&gt; for each concept I have: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;KeyResult&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;an &lt;em&gt;edge&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ObjectiveToKeyResult&lt;/code&gt; to show which key results are associated with which objectives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriusweb/view.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semantics forever!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last point (and I promise after that you can go back to normal activity), with Sirius Web you can also specify behaviors associated with your data. For instance, in my diagram I want to see what are the objectives I have checked and the one still to work on.
I describe a conditional style on my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Objective&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;red while is not yet completed,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;green when all the key results are set to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Done&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriusweb/studio.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your studio is alive!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what do you have to do next? Nothing! Just try your new dedicated tool! Sirius Web manages everything for you.
Without doing anything to deploy, I can use my new diagram by creating a new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TodoList&lt;/code&gt; and opening the associated representation.
I can create new objectives and new key results, set their attributes and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriusweb/studio.gif&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I go back to my tooling’s expectations, using Sirius Web I can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;task-list&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;represent&lt;/strong&gt; and edit my &lt;strong&gt;data graphically&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;task-list-item&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; class=&quot;task-list-item-checkbox&quot; disabled=&quot;disabled&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;enhance my dataset&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to &lt;strong&gt;semantics&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give it a try!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want to try it by yourself, this is possible, just create an account on our online demo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.obeostudio.com&quot;&gt;https://demo.obeostudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.
You have any questions about Sirius Web or OCP, contact me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as usual I am thankful to all our customers for their support of Sirius Web!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">TLDR; This post is for you if you want to build web-based graphical modeling tools. Eclipse Sirius is an open source project to create domain-specific modeling workbenches.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Happy New 2022.01.0!</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/04/happy-new-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy New 2022.01.0!" /><published>2022-02-04T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-02-04T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/04/happy-new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2022/02/04/happy-new-year/">&lt;p&gt;I know… I am late for an happy new year but I am not for an Happy New &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/#_version_2022_01_0&quot;&gt;2022.01.0&lt;/a&gt;!
I’m in a dancing mood while I’m writing this… (and poor you) an idea comes to my mind: &lt;em&gt;“Why not associating a song to each new features?”&lt;/em&gt;
It could be &lt;em&gt;funny&lt;/em&gt; and you’ll result with a (terrible) soundtrack to play with this new version.
Follow me for a &lt;em&gt;musical&lt;/em&gt; ride through the new Sirius Web and OCP features!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calendar versioning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://youtu.be/EIbuf0iZKq8&quot;&gt;
January, February, March, April, May&lt;br /&gt;
June, July&lt;br /&gt;
January, February, March, April, May&lt;br /&gt;
June, July
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;—Boney M., &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/EIbuf0iZKq8&quot;&gt;Calendar song&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For two years now, we have been working hard on &lt;a href=&quot;http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/13/sirius-web/&quot;&gt;Sirius Web in the open&lt;/a&gt;. Since the last 2021.12.0 version, Sirius Web released its first stable version. Since that point, we will take care not to break (too much) APIs for our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-sirius/sirius-components&quot;&gt;Sirius Components&lt;/a&gt; consumers. We decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-sirius/sirius-components/blob/master/doc/adrs/034_switch_from_semver_to_calver.adoc&quot;&gt;switch from semantic versioning to calendar versioning&lt;/a&gt; to reflect the maturity of the project.
We will keep our development cycle with six weeks of work and two weeks for various minor improvements for each release.
Once a stable release “YEAR.MONTH.0” is done, we will start working on the next one “YEAR.MONTH+2.0”. During the preparation of the next release, we will improve the current branch to prepare for that release. As a result, we will have multiple intermediate releases with a YEAR.MONTH.1, YEAR.MONTH.2… YEAR.MONTH.42, etc. Those releases should be considered as milestones for the next stable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The changes made are tracked in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eclipse-sirius/sirius-components/blob/master/CHANGELOG.adoc&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/a&gt; where you can find a fine grain list of all the API breaks, new features, bug fixes and various improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magic connector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0p_1QSUsbsM&quot;&gt;
It's a kind of magic&lt;br /&gt;
It's a kind of magic&lt;br /&gt;
A kind of magic (No way)&lt;br /&gt;
One dream, one &lt;b&gt;CONNECTOR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;—&lt;i&gt;Almost&lt;/i&gt; Queen, &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0p_1QSUsbsM&quot;&gt;A Kind of Magic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/2022.01.0/img/MagicConnector.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Connector&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;em&gt;“Magic Connector”&lt;/em&gt; tool is available on diagrams. It provides an alternative way to create edges between diagram elements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose the generic &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Connector&lt;/code&gt; tool from the source node’s palette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;select the target node&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;choose which of the compatible tools to apply in the menu appears. If there is only one compatible tool, it will be applied automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DnD for Unsync diagram&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://youtu.be/ALanRqbNSvI?t=895&quot;&gt;
Accepts she's out of sync&lt;br /&gt;
She's out of sync (sync)&lt;br /&gt;
She's out of sync (sync)&lt;br /&gt;
She's out of sync&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;—Devo, &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ALanRqbNSvI?t=895&quot;&gt;Out of sync&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/#_version_2021_10_0&quot;&gt;2021.10.0&lt;/a&gt; release, it is possible to create unsynchronized diagram with Sirius Web. It means a diagram which may not display all elements provided by the studio, but only the elements that the user selected.
At that time we added support for deleting view without deleting the corresponding semantic element (aka “Delete from Diagram”) for unsynchronized diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2022.01.0/deletefromdiagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now also possible to drag semantic elements from the explorer on a diagram. The concrete effect depends on how the target diagram is defined, but a typical case is to add a graphical representation of the dropped element on the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/2022.01.0/img/DropFromExplorer.gif&quot; alt=&quot;DnD&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fit to Screen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://youtu.be/PzilYDj2b9k&quot;&gt;
Now it fits you good&lt;br /&gt;
Oh fits you good&lt;br /&gt;
Yeah fits you good&lt;br /&gt;
Oh fits you good&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;—Bryan Adams, &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PzilYDj2b9k&quot;&gt;Fits Ya good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a diagram is opened, a “Fit to screen” is automatically performed to ensure all its content is visible. Previously, depending on the coordinates of the elements it could happen that not all of them were visible on open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/2022.01.0/img/FitToScreenOnOpen.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Fit to screen&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stylish studios!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://youtu.be/-CmadmM5cOk&quot;&gt;
'Cause we never go out of style,
we never go out of style
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;—Taylor Swift, &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/-CmadmM5cOk&quot;&gt;Style&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release after release we continue to improve the web studio definition capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nodes can now have a dynamically computed size (using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Size Expression&lt;/code&gt;) which depends on the current state of the semantic model. If the expression is present and produces a positive integer, it will be used as both the width and height of the node, in pixels. Currently it is not possible to compute different values for width and height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2022.01.0/sizenodedef.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2022.01.0/sizenode.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to define border nodes in web studio definition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2022.01.0/bordernode.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, it is possible to configure text style on labels: &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;u&gt;underline&lt;/u&gt;, &lt;del&gt;strike-through&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/2022.01.0/style.png&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Obeo team has started a new iteration to preprare 2022.03.0, we focus on three topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support of &lt;strong&gt;Component-like diagrams&lt;/strong&gt; with ports and bendpoints for edges,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diagram user experience&lt;/strong&gt; to smoothly edit, move, reconnect and layout diagrams,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And…(drum roll)… &lt;strong&gt;Tables&lt;/strong&gt;! I am really enthusiastic about this one, we are cooking something really cool!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed release notes for &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.obeostudio.com/#_version_2022_01_0&quot;&gt;2022.01.0&lt;/a&gt; is available in our online documentation: &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.obeostudio.com&quot;&gt;http://docs.obeostudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, all these changes are made available thanks to our loved customers sponsoring the Sirius Web open source project! Do not hesitate to join the party and become a Sirius Web supporter, it is as easy as sending me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you soon for the next Sirius Web and OCP &lt;del&gt;soundtrack&lt;/del&gt; release!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">I know… I am late for an happy new year but I am not for an Happy New 2022.01.0! I’m in a dancing mood while I’m writing this… (and poor you) an idea comes to my mind: “Why not associating a song to each new features?” It could be funny and you’ll result with a (terrible) soundtrack to play with this new version. Follow me for a musical ride through the new Sirius Web and OCP features!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alice’s adventures in Sirius Web Land</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2021/10/11/econ21/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alice’s adventures in Sirius Web Land" /><published>2021-10-11T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-10-11T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2021/10/11/econ21</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2021/10/11/econ21/">&lt;p&gt;Since my early childhood I have loved stories, listening to books read by my mum, then reading by myself comics or classical literature for school and now, as I dedicate not so much time to reading, mostly blog posts and news on the internet.
One of my favorite novels remains “Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland”.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/econ21/alice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice's Adventures in Wonderland&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young girl named Alice falls through a rabbit hole into a fantastic world of weird creatures. She meets people, she experiences, she tastes, she has to make decisions, sometimes she’s scared, and the minute after she’s happy. This book is like a roller coaster full of events and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about our job at Obeo, when we have to create a tool dedicated to a specific domain for one of our customers, I feel like we are all small Alices experiencing the Sirius Land.
We start by meeting people, trying to understand their jobs, their needs, we make decisions about what concepts we will specify, how they will be represented… Sometimes it works “Yes! I did it!” and sometimes the user’s feedback is not so good and we rework the tool “Oh, no, try again ;(“…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago, we at Obeo released a fist version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; project and I had this little Alice in mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice was beginning to get very tired of creating DSL graphical editors and of having too many things to do: start Eclipse, describe her domain with Ecore, generate the EMF code, launch another Eclipse runtime, specify her graphical mappings with Sirius Desktop, test with another Eclipse runtime, package everything to an update site, send it to Bob so that he can install it, help Bob who can’t find how to install the modeler, reiterate from the beginning to update the tool according to Bob feedbacks and needs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh dear! Would you tell me, please, which way I ought to go from here?” she asked,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That depends a good deal on where you want to get to,” said the Cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice prayed for a framework to easily create and deploy her studios to the web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiouser and curiouser! This exists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a talk at EclipseCon 2021 to tell you about Alice in Sirius Web Land!
In this session, I will introduce and demonstrate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;describe your domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;specify your graphical editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;deploy&lt;/strong&gt; your studio to your end-users
… everything &lt;strong&gt;from your browser&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;thanks to Sirius Web&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a dream, this is really happening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/econ21/mm.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sirius Web Domain and View definitions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will demonstrate all examples using 100% open-source software. Come and join me! You have no excuse, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2021/registration&quot;&gt;register at EclipseCon&lt;/a&gt;. As it is a virtual event you can attend from anywhere, even from Wonderland!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">Since my early childhood I have loved stories, listening to books read by my mum, then reading by myself comics or classical literature for school and now, as I dedicate not so much time to reading, mostly blog posts and news on the internet. One of my favorite novels remains “Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Scene #4</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2021/04/29/behind-the-scene-list-container/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Scene #4" /><published>2021-04-29T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-04-29T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2021/04/29/behind-the-scene-list-container</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2021/04/29/behind-the-scene-list-container/">&lt;p&gt;I am happy to present you the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt; session.
Here and now, Guillaume Coutable, Consultant at Obeo, gives a demonstration of the list container support he is working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2xHeAhfYzO4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thankful to all our customers for their support to Sirius Web!
See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt; session!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">I am happy to present you the new Sirius Web “Behind the scene” session. Here and now, Guillaume Coutable, Consultant at Obeo, gives a demonstration of the list container support he is working on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Scene #3</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2021/03/31/behind-the-scene-layout/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Scene #3" /><published>2021-03-31T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-03-31T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2021/03/31/behind-the-scene-layout</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2021/03/31/behind-the-scene-layout/">&lt;p&gt;And here it is! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt; third session.
I am pleased to give the stage to Florian Barbin, Consultant at Obeo.
He gives a short tour of the new incremental layout he developed with William Piers based on Thales needs.
We are very grateful to our customers for contributing to Sirius Web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S8s8GmEOWqQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">And here it is! The Sirius Web “Behind the scene” third session. I am pleased to give the stage to Florian Barbin, Consultant at Obeo. He gives a short tour of the new incremental layout he developed with William Piers based on Thales needs. We are very grateful to our customers for contributing to Sirius Web!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Scene</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2021/02/19/behind-the-scene-ide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Scene" /><published>2021-02-19T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-19T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2021/02/19/behind-the-scene-ide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2021/02/19/behind-the-scene-ide/">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt;.
For this second session, I invited Axel Richard, Consultant at Obeo to present his work on the integration of the Sirius Web Diagramming Component with Cloud IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jyPyH5F-cxo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our customers for helping in financing this development around Sirius Web.
See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">Welcome to another Sirius Web “Behind the scene”. For this second session, I invited Axel Richard, Consultant at Obeo to present his work on the integration of the Sirius Web Diagramming Component with Cloud IDEs.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Behind the Scene</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2021/01/27/behind-the-scene-diag/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behind the Scene" /><published>2021-01-27T11:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-27T11:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2021/01/27/behind-the-scene-diag</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2021/01/27/behind-the-scene-diag/">&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year Obeo open sourced a new project at the Eclipse Foundation : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt;.
Sirius web is a framework to easily create and deploy modeling studios to the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirius web is evolving a lot and we would like to share with the community these on-going enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to introduce a new regular series of videos: &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene of Sirius Web”&lt;/em&gt;.
The goal is to show you in 1-2 minutes each month what we are working on in the Sirius Web project.
For this first session, I invited Stéphane Begaudeau, Software Architect of Sirius Web to present his work on the Diagramming Component that aims at making this component easier to reuse in any web environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NcHkfSwPqzw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our customers for helping in financing this development around Sirius Web.
See you next month for another “Behind the scene”!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">At the end of last year Obeo open sourced a new project at the Eclipse Foundation : Sirius Web. Sirius web is a framework to easily create and deploy modeling studios to the web.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">T-4:00 OCP is ready to go</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/17/ocp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-4:00 OCP is ready to go" /><published>2020-10-17T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-17T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/17/ocp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/17/ocp/">&lt;p&gt;Atop the Sirius-II Mission’s rocket is the Obeo Cloud Platform (OCP), with two flavors – OCP Modeler and OCP Publication – safely strapped inside.
The Obeo Cloud Platform is built as an open-core product relying on the open source Eclipse Sirius project (EPL 2.0 licence) and more precisely on the Sirius Web component. As I explained in my previous post, Sirius Web is a framework from Obeo for building cloud graphical modelers for a dedicated DSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ocp-publication&quot;&gt;OCP Publication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCP Publication exposes models in a read-only mode for fast access from OSLC clients or web browsers. The first version of this product is ready to be deployed to our customers at the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/OCP_Publication.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first use cases we developed allows us to reunite two of our chosen fields: Capella and model servers, it is Publication For Capella. Publication for Capella provides a tight integration between OSLC-compliant ALM tools (Polarion, Doors Next…) and the MBSE workbench Capella. It enables a fine grained traceability between your requirements and your system design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ocp-modeler&quot;&gt;OCP Modeler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCP Modeler is a unique technology to easily develop custom and state-of-the-art modeling tools to be deployed to the Cloud.
The Obeo Cloud Platform Modeler is a Sirius Web build extended with Enterprise features, to deploy on public, private clouds or on premise and including support and upgrade guarantees.
The Obeo Cloud Platform provides collaborative features: authentication, live collaboration, webhooks…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wKV6ePnPwvw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get more details, attend the OCP Modeler’s launch on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">Atop the Sirius-II Mission’s rocket is the Obeo Cloud Platform (OCP), with two flavors – OCP Modeler and OCP Publication – safely strapped inside. The Obeo Cloud Platform is built as an open-core product relying on the open source Eclipse Sirius project (EPL 2.0 licence) and more precisely on the Sirius Web component. As I explained in my previous post, Sirius Web is a framework from Obeo for building cloud graphical modelers for a dedicated DSL.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">T-8:00 1st stage Sirius Web loading begins</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/13/sirius-web/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-8:00 1st stage Sirius Web loading begins" /><published>2020-10-13T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/13/sirius-web</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/13/sirius-web/">&lt;p&gt;Source code is flowing into the first stage of the Obeo rocket. Our goal is to bring the spirit of Sirius into a new technological space : Sirius Web is the Cloud-based evolution of Sirius, 100% Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebTimeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sirius Web engine combines the open source components EMF-JSON &amp;amp; Sirius Components. These components will be available under the Sirius project : &lt;a href=&quot;http://eclipse.org/sirius&quot;&gt;http://eclipse.org/sirius&lt;/a&gt;, with the source code on Github :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMF-JSON&lt;/strong&gt; is a small library to serialize EMF models to JSON,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sirius Components&lt;/strong&gt; repository provides backend and frontend components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/strong&gt; repository combines the open source Sirius components to provide a graphical modeler sample application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebArchitecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-create-a-cloud-ready-modeler-based-on-sirius-web&quot;&gt;How do you create a cloud-ready modeler based on Sirius Web?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define your metamodel thanks to EMF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a Sirius configuration to specify the mapping between the different concepts of your DSL and how they should be represented graphically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Register the metamodel &amp;amp; the Sirius specification in the Sirius Web application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build and launch the application!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebServer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you get a graphical modeler dedicated to your DSL rendered in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IXXxOCbEjE4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get more details about Sirius Web and how to run it for your own DSL, attend Obeo’s rocket liftoff.
Launch remains on schedule for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">Source code is flowing into the first stage of the Obeo rocket. Our goal is to bring the spirit of Sirius into a new technological space : Sirius Web is the Cloud-based evolution of Sirius, 100% Open Source.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">T-16:00 Obeo approves “load-and-go” fueling: EMF-JSON onboard!</title><link href="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/05/emf-json/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="T-16:00 Obeo approves “load-and-go” fueling: EMF-JSON onboard!" /><published>2020-10-05T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2020-10-05T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/05/emf-json</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://melb.enix.org/2020/10/05/emf-json/">&lt;p&gt;At Nantes Dev Force Station Launch Complex 42A, valves are open and code source is beginning to flow into Obeo’s rocket. The first open source project released by the SIRIUS-II Mission is: EMF-JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EMF-JSON project will soon be part of the Eclipse Sirius project. It provides a JSON-based implementation of EMF resources which can be used as a drop-in replacement for the default XMI-based format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BbipffAatgY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is part of Sirius, this new EMF resource type can actually be used by any EMF-based application as it does not depend on the rest of the Sirius platform (neither the existing Sirius Desktop nor the upcoming Sirius Web).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liftoff on the SIRIUS-II mission to the Eclipse Foundation remains planned for an instantaneous launch window on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mélanie Bats</name></author><category term="planet" /><summary type="html">At Nantes Dev Force Station Launch Complex 42A, valves are open and code source is beginning to flow into Obeo’s rocket. The first open source project released by the SIRIUS-II Mission is: EMF-JSON.</summary></entry></feed>