<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
  <title>MelBlog - planet</title>
  <description>Posts tagged as 'planet'</description>
     <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feeds/feed.planet.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://localhost:4000/tag/planet/</link>
  <updated>2021-10-13T15:30:42+02:00</updated>
  <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
  </author>

  
   <item>
    <title>Alice’s adventures in Sirius Web Land</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my early childhood I have loved stories, listening to books read by my mum, then reading by myself comics or classical literature for school and now, as I dedicate not so much time to reading, mostly blog posts and news on the internet.
One of my favorite novels remains “Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland”.
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/econ21/alice.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alice's Adventures in Wonderland&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young girl named Alice falls through a rabbit hole into a fantastic world of weird creatures. She meets people, she experiences, she tastes, she has to make decisions, sometimes she’s scared, and the minute after she’s happy. This book is like a roller coaster full of events and emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I think about our job at Obeo, when we have to create a tool dedicated to a specific domain for one of our customers, I feel like we are all small Alices experiencing the Sirius Land.
We start by meeting people, trying to understand their jobs, their needs, we make decisions about what concepts we will specify, how they will be represented… Sometimes it works “Yes! I did it!” and sometimes the user’s feedback is not so good and we rework the tool “Oh, no, try again ;(“…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year ago, we at Obeo released a fist version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; project and I had this little Alice in mind…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice was beginning to get very tired of creating DSL graphical editors and of having too many things to do: start Eclipse, describe her domain with Ecore, generate the EMF code, launch another Eclipse runtime, specify her graphical mappings with Sirius Desktop, test with another Eclipse runtime, package everything to an update site, send it to Bob so that he can install it, help Bob who can’t find how to install the modeler, reiterate from the beginning to update the tool according to Bob feedbacks and needs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh dear! Would you tell me, please, which way I ought to go from here?” she asked,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That depends a good deal on where you want to get to,” said the Cat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice prayed for a framework to easily create and deploy her studios to the web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curiouser and curiouser! This exists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a talk at EclipseCon 2021 to tell you about Alice in Sirius Web Land!
In this session, I will introduce and demonstrate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;describe your domain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;specify your graphical editor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to &lt;strong&gt;deploy&lt;/strong&gt; your studio to your end-users
… everything &lt;strong&gt;from your browser&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;thanks to Sirius Web&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not a dream, this is really happening!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/econ21/mm.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Sirius Web Domain and View definitions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will demonstrate all examples using 100% open-source software. Come and join me! You have no excuse, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2021/registration&quot;&gt;register at EclipseCon&lt;/a&gt;. As it is a virtual event you can attend from anywhere, even from Wonderland!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/10/11/econ21/ </link>
    <pubDate>2021-10-11T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/10/11/econ21/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Behind the Scene #4</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to present you the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt; session.
Here and now, Guillaume Coutable, Consultant at Obeo, gives a demonstration of the list container support he is working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2xHeAhfYzO4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thankful to all our customers for their support to Sirius Web!
See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt; session!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/behind-the-scene-list-container/ </link>
    <pubDate>2021-04-29T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/04/29/behind-the-scene-list-container/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Behind the Scene #3</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;And here it is! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt; third session.
I am pleased to give the stage to Florian Barbin, Consultant at Obeo.
He gives a short tour of the new incremental layout he developed with William Piers based on Thales needs.
We are very grateful to our customers for contributing to Sirius Web!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/S8s8GmEOWqQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/31/behind-the-scene-layout/ </link>
    <pubDate>2021-03-31T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/03/31/behind-the-scene-layout/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Behind the Scene</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/em&gt;.
For this second session, I invited Axel Richard, Consultant at Obeo to present his work on the integration of the Sirius Web Diagramming Component with Cloud IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jyPyH5F-cxo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our customers for helping in financing this development around Sirius Web.
See you next month for another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NcHkfSwPqzw&amp;amp;list=PLRWQgLDUlJCj-Ri4hWkfyHaYWxW7LurBf&quot;&gt;“Behind the scene”&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/02/19/behind-the-scene-ide/ </link>
    <pubDate>2021-02-19T11:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/02/19/behind-the-scene-ide/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>Behind the Scene</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year Obeo open sourced a new project at the Eclipse Foundation : &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/sirius-web.html&quot;&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/a&gt;.
Sirius web is a framework to easily create and deploy modeling studios to the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sirius web is evolving a lot and we would like to share with the community these on-going enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to introduce a new regular series of videos: &lt;em&gt;“Behind the scene of Sirius Web”&lt;/em&gt;.
The goal is to show you in 1-2 minutes each month what we are working on in the Sirius Web project.
For this first session, I invited Stéphane Begaudeau, Software Architect of Sirius Web to present his work on the Diagramming Component that aims at making this component easier to reuse in any web environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NcHkfSwPqzw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all our customers for helping in financing this development around Sirius Web.
See you next month for another “Behind the scene”!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/01/27/behind-the-scene-diag/ </link>
    <pubDate>2021-01-27T11:00:00+01:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/01/27/behind-the-scene-diag/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>T-4:00 OCP is ready to go</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Atop the Sirius-II Mission’s rocket is the Obeo Cloud Platform (OCP), with two flavors – OCP Modeler and OCP Publication – safely strapped inside.
The Obeo Cloud Platform is built as an open-core product relying on the open source Eclipse Sirius project (EPL 2.0 licence) and more precisely on the Sirius Web component. As I explained in my previous post, Sirius Web is a framework from Obeo for building cloud graphical modelers for a dedicated DSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ocp-publication&quot;&gt;OCP Publication&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCP Publication exposes models in a read-only mode for fast access from OSLC clients or web browsers. The first version of this product is ready to be deployed to our customers at the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/OCP_Publication.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first use cases we developed allows us to reunite two of our chosen fields: Capella and model servers, it is Publication For Capella. Publication for Capella provides a tight integration between OSLC-compliant ALM tools (Polarion, Doors Next…) and the MBSE workbench Capella. It enables a fine grained traceability between your requirements and your system design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ocp-modeler&quot;&gt;OCP Modeler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCP Modeler is a unique technology to easily develop custom and state-of-the-art modeling tools to be deployed to the Cloud.
The Obeo Cloud Platform Modeler is a Sirius Web build extended with Enterprise features, to deploy on public, private clouds or on premise and including support and upgrade guarantees.
The Obeo Cloud Platform provides collaborative features: authentication, live collaboration, webhooks…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wKV6ePnPwvw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get more details, attend the OCP Modeler’s launch on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/17/ocp/ </link>
    <pubDate>2020-10-17T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/10/17/ocp/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>T-8:00 1st stage Sirius Web loading begins</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;Source code is flowing into the first stage of the Obeo rocket. Our goal is to bring the spirit of Sirius into a new technological space : Sirius Web is the Cloud-based evolution of Sirius, 100% Open Source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebTimeline.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sirius Web engine combines the open source components EMF-JSON &amp;amp; Sirius Components. These components will be available under the Sirius project : &lt;a href=&quot;http://eclipse.org/sirius&quot;&gt;http://eclipse.org/sirius&lt;/a&gt;, with the source code on Github :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMF-JSON&lt;/strong&gt; is a small library to serialize EMF models to JSON,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sirius Components&lt;/strong&gt; repository provides backend and frontend components&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Sirius Web&lt;/strong&gt; repository combines the open source Sirius components to provide a graphical modeler sample application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebArchitecture.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-do-you-create-a-cloud-ready-modeler-based-on-sirius-web&quot;&gt;How do you create a cloud-ready modeler based on Sirius Web?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define your metamodel thanks to EMF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a Sirius configuration to specify the mapping between the different concepts of your DSL and how they should be represented graphically.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Register the metamodel &amp;amp; the Sirius specification in the Sirius Web application.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build and launch the application!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/sirius-web/SiriusWebServer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, you get a graphical modeler dedicated to your DSL rendered in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IXXxOCbEjE4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get more details about Sirius Web and how to run it for your own DSL, attend Obeo’s rocket liftoff.
Launch remains on schedule for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/13/sirius-web/ </link>
    <pubDate>2020-10-13T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/10/13/sirius-web/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>T-16:00 Obeo approves “load-and-go” fueling: EMF-JSON onboard!</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;At Nantes Dev Force Station Launch Complex 42A, valves are open and code source is beginning to flow into Obeo’s rocket. The first open source project released by the SIRIUS-II Mission is: EMF-JSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EMF-JSON project will soon be part of the Eclipse Sirius project. It provides a JSON-based implementation of EMF resources which can be used as a drop-in replacement for the default XMI-based format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BbipffAatgY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it is part of Sirius, this new EMF resource type can actually be used by any EMF-based application as it does not depend on the rest of the Sirius platform (neither the existing Sirius Desktop nor the upcoming Sirius Web).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liftoff on the SIRIUS-II mission to the Eclipse Foundation remains planned for an instantaneous launch window on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;October 21 at 2:00 p.m CET&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/10/05/emf-json/ </link>
    <pubDate>2020-10-05T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/10/05/emf-json/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>SIRIUS-II Mission</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;On &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, October 21 at 2:00 p.m. CEST&lt;/strong&gt;, Obeo’s Spacecraft 42 will launch the SIRIUS-II mission from Code Launch Complex 42 (CLC-42) at Nantes Dev Force Station in France. SIRIUS-I mission previously launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/&quot;&gt;Sirius&lt;/a&gt; to the Eclipse Foundation with Obeo’s &amp;amp; Thales astronauts on board back in 2013. The first mission was a success with the adoption of Sirius Desktop, based on the Eclipse platform, by a large community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SIRIUS-II Mission aims to &lt;strong&gt;release Sirius Web&lt;/strong&gt;, the Cloud-based evolution of Sirius, 100% Open Source. This mission is also in charge of &lt;strong&gt;the launch of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.obeo.fr/en/products/obeo-cloud-platform&quot;&gt;Obeo Cloud Platform&lt;/a&gt; (OCP)&lt;/strong&gt;, the solution offered by Obeo for deploying modeling tools to the web.
With Sirius Web, modeling tools developed with Sirius can be installed on a web server and are rendered in a browser. Our goal is to carry the spirit of Sirius into a new technological space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for the Sirius Web/OCP countdown by following &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melaniebats&quot;&gt;@melaniebats&lt;/a&gt; twitter account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All Times Are Approximate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;DAY:MIN&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;EVENT&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-64:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Sirius-II Mission announcement&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-32:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Crew access arm retracts&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-24:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Obeo Launch Director verifies “go” for code load&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-16:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;EMF-JSON loading begins&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-08:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;1st stage Sirius Web loading begins&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-04:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;2nd stage OCP loading begins&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-02:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Obeo begins engine chill prior to launch&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-01:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Command flight computer to begin final prelaunch checks&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-00:42&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Obeo Launch Director verifies “go” for launch&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-00:03&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Engine controller commands engine ignition sequence to start&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T-00:00&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Sirius Web and OCP liftoff&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;T+00:30&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;SIRIUS-II deployment&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following stage separation, Obeo will land Spacecraft 42’s first stage on the Eclipse Foundation codeship, which will be stationed in the Atlantic Ocean. The SIRIUS-II spacecraft will be deployed about 30 minutes after liftoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can attend a live of the launch by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/registration&quot;&gt;registering to EclipseCon 2020&lt;/a&gt; and choosing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipsecon.org/2020/sessions/sirius-web-100-open-source-cloud-modeling-platform&quot;&gt;Sirius Web: 100% open source cloud modeling platform&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/18/siriusiimission/ </link>
    <pubDate>2020-08-18T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/08/18/siriusiimission/</guid>
   </item>
  
   <item>
    <title>SiriusCon 2020: Sirius to the Web with Obeo Cloud Platform</title>
    <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TLDR; On June 18th connect to @SiriusCon Live 2020 to watch a demo of the Obeo Cloud Platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriuscon2020/announcement.png&quot; alt=&quot;Here we go again&quot; title=&quot;Here we go again&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Mamma mia, does it show again &lt;br /&gt;
My my, just how much I’ve missed you?“ &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/unfzfe8f9NI&quot;&gt;Mamma Mia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of June, I will have the pleasure of presenting the Obeo Cloud Platform, with my co-speaker &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sbegaudeau&quot;&gt;Stéphane Bégaudeau&lt;/a&gt;, at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siriuscon.org/&quot;&gt;SiriusCon Live 2020&lt;/a&gt;.
During SiriusCon 2020, we will not only demonstrate OCP, but also make a big announcement about its future. So, attend SiriusCon and be in for a huge surprise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After such a long time, it is great to be able to connect with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eclipse.org/sirius&quot;&gt;Eclipse Sirius&lt;/a&gt; community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have to create a graphical modeling workbench for your own DSL, then you know how powerful Sirius is to help you design your own modeler based on EMF. In just a few hours, you get a modeling studio dedicated to your &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eclipse.org/sirius/gallery.html&quot;&gt;own domain&lt;/a&gt;.
The main issue faced by our customers arises when they need to distribute the bundle to their end users. A truly effective deployment is difficult to come by. Many struggle to either deploy or maintain their solution. And their team are feeling the pinch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To solve these challenges, I am excited to demonstrate the Obeo Cloud Platform (OCP), the Cloud-based solution developed by Obeo for deploying modeling tools to the web. With OCP Modeler, modeling tools developed with Sirius can be installed on a Cloud server and are rendered in a web browser. Our purpose is to carry the spirit of Sirius.
What our users typically love in Sirius is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the ability to define your modeling workbench in a configuration file,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no code generation involved as everything is interpreted at runtime,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flexible even for complex models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we kept all those principles and now allow you to easily define workbenches running in the cloud.
We rebuilt the Sirius runtime from the ground up, for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been talking about it for a long time now! And we’re really proud to show that OCP is available and working today, so our talk will be purely a live demo: no slides (almost), no bullet points, not feature lists. Just us, showing the capabilities of this modeling environment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriuscon2020/ocp.png&quot; alt=&quot;OCP Modeler&quot; title=&quot;OCP Modeler&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will give you as well an overview of the context, the roadmap and how OCP Modeler positions with Sirius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Referring to ABBA’s words, take a chance on OCP!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Honey I’m still free &lt;br /&gt;
Take a chance on me &lt;br /&gt;
Gonna do my very best, baby can’t you see &lt;br /&gt;
Gotta put me to the test, take a chance on me“ &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/-crgQGdpZR0&quot;&gt;Take a chance on me&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, as a preparation, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/xFrGuyw1V8s&quot;&gt;you can dance, you can djibe&lt;/a&gt; and most importantly you have to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/Register_SiriusCon2020&quot;&gt;register&lt;/a&gt;. And no, even if I am a big #ABBAFan the surprise is not that I will do my talk in a fancy glittering costume… neither Stéphane even if it could be very memorable :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/siriuscon2020/dancing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dancing&quot; title=&quot;Dancing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/10/siriuscon/ </link>
    <pubDate>2020-06-10T12:00:00+02:00</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/06/10/siriuscon/</guid>
   </item>
  
 </channel>
</rss>